Guide to the Western Sahara Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Western Sahara collection
1976-1997
MS 1555
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.5
(2 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material relating to political conditions in Western Sahara.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection, MS 605; African Postcard Collection, MS 1575; Pamphlet Collection, MS 1351. Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The material in the original accession is arranged chronologically. Additions to the collection may vary in arrangement.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material relating to political conditions in Western Sahara.
Western Sahara -- Politics and government
- Original Accession, 1976-1992
  - Newspapers, 1976, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Africa Fund: newsletters, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Association des Amis de la République Arabe Sahraouie Démocratique (R.A.S.D.): bulletins, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 20 Mai: Organe Central du Front Populaire pour la Libération de Saguia el Hamra et Rio de Oro, 1980 August (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Saharan/Saharawi Peoples Support Committee: newsletters, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Western Sahara Newsletter, 1988-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Western Sahara Campaign (WSC): brochure, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - "10 Años Que Cambiaron España, 1973-1983," Historia de la transición, Diario 16, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Referendum por la independencia del Sahara: flyers, stickers, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fernando Poo-Rio Muni, Sahara-Ifni: map, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1976-1997; Accession 1996-M-010
  Scope and Contents
  Also includes Accession 2010-M-119
  - Il Semana Cultural Saharaui [event program], 1997 March 10-16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Temboury, Pedro [former Spanish ambassador to Senegal, Mauritania, and the Ivory Coast; copy of his notes for a lecture delivered at summer courses, University of Complutense, Madrid], 1994 July (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Western Sahara Campaign News [issues 1 and 2], 1985, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Western Sahara Report [vol. 5, no. 5], 1984 June-July (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Media Luna Roja Saharui: Bulletin d'Information, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resistance Sahraouie, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Resistance Sahraouie: Sahraoui Vervet, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Western Sahara Awareness Project (WESAP)--briefing on Western Sahara, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)